A Guide to the Bland Family King and Queen County Records, 1794-1864
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Bland Family King and Queen County Records, 1794-1864
The Library of Virginia
24097
75 leaves, negative photostats
Bland Family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Lent for copying, 18 December 1953, by Mrs. J. D. Hutchinson, Walkerton, Virginia.
Biographical Information
The Bland family was a prominent family in King and Queen County, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Records, 1794-1864, of the Bland family of King and Queen County, Virginia, consisting of deeds, 1794-1851, for property in King and Queen County, for a mill, mill seat, and waterpower fixtures, for share of the estate of Henry Dixon, deceased, and for a match of bay horses; plats, 1809-1832 and no date, of land in King and Queen County; decree, 14 March 1836, from the King and Queen County Court in suit of John G. Muire vs Eleanor and Richard Moore; will, 4 October 1848, of Nancy Newcomb; minutes, 3 June 1850, of the meeting of the Board of Overseers of the Poor of King and Queen County; agreement, 5 March 1860, between Sarah Spencer on the one part and William W. Spencer, et. al. for all rights to Sarah Spencer's dower and share in her deceased husband's estate; and notes, 1861 and 1864, issued by King and Queen County and signed by Robert Pollard.
Contents List
- Plat, no date, of 398 acres belonging to the estate of Michael Dickson by Samuel May.
- Deed, dated and recorded 14 April 1794, for 146 acres from William Bland to Ralph Bland.
- Plat, made 21 February 1809 and copied 18 May 1818, of 93 1/4 acred belonging to the estate of John Carr, plat made by John Carlton and copied by Christopher Carlton.
- Deed, dated 24 January 1823 and recorded 10 February 1823, for 94 acres from Mildred G. Blake of Mathews County, Virginia, to John Bland.
- Deed, 28 December 1824, for their share in the estate of Henry Dixon from Charles and Louisa Atkinson to John Jessee, Jessee relinquished his claim to John Bland, Jr., 8 December 1825.
- Deed, dated 3 December 1825 and recorded 12 December 1825, for 94 acres from John Mann, William Farinholt, and Thomas Dudley to John Bland, Jr.
- Deed, dated 4 April 1829 and recorded 13 April 1829, for 11 acres from Thomas and Caroline Dudley to John Bland, Jr.
- Deed, dated 22 May 1829 and recorded 8 June 1829, for 98 1/4 acres from James A. and Frances Walden to Roderick Bland.
- Plat, 7 November 1832, for 32 acres belonging to Nancy Haywood by John Mann.
- Deed, dated 3 November 1832 and recorded 10 December 1832, for 22 acres from Thomas Crittenden to Roderick Bland.
- Deed, dated 17 September 1833 and recorded 20 December 1833, for right and title to certain property from Fleming Padget to John Mann.
- Decree, 14 March 1836, from the King and Queen County Court in suit of John G. Muire vs Eleanor and Richard Moore.
- Deed, dated 2 April 1836 and recorded 9 May 1836, for 40 acres from John Summerson to John Bland, Jr.
- Deed, dated 8 February 1837 and recorded 13 February 1837, for 32 acres from William Haywood, Elizabeth Haywood, Benjamin Haywood, John Haywood, Nancy Haywood, and Sarah Haywood to John Bland.
- Deed, dated 31 December 1836 and recorded 14 March 1837, for 37 acres from John Bland, Sr. to John Bland.
- Deed, 16 July 1846, for a match of bay horses from Alexander Gilliam of Richmond, Virginia, to Roderick Bland.
- Deed, dated 18 July 1846 and recorded 10 August 1846, for 133 acres from Richard Shackelford to Roderick Bland.
- Will, 4 October 1848, of Nancy Newcomb.
- Deed, dated 14 October 1848 and recorded 11 December 1848, for 40 acres from Peter and Harriet Broocke to Henry Williams.
- Deed, dated 16 February 1850 and recorded 11 March 1850, for 269 acres from George W. Booker, Commissioner, to Roderick Bland.
- Minutes, 3 June 1850, of the meeting of the Board of Overseers of the Poor of King and Queen County.
- Deed, dated 13 June 1851 and recorded 11 August 1851, for a mill, mill seat, and waterpower fixtures from Richard G. Smith to Roderick and Absolom Bland.
- Agreement, 5 March 1860, between Sarah Spencer on the one part and William W. Spencer, John Spencer, James S. Bristow, and Laurence Anderson for all rights to Sarah Spencer's dower and share in the estate of her deceased husband John Spencer.
- Two notes, 1 July 1861, for $10 issued by King and Queen County and signed by Robert Pollard, clerk of court, to John R. Bagby or bearer.
- Notes, 1 August 1864, for $100 issued by King and Queen County and signed by Robert Pollard to "bearer."